<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="website.xsl"?>
<page id="devel">
	<meta>
		<title>SimME DevDocs - Development Environment</title>
	</meta>

<body>
	<section><title>SimME - Development Environment</title>

		<p>In here there are several tips and advices on how to help develop SimME.
		As developing for the Java 2 Micro Edition (J2ME) is not very complicated,
		this document is made short. It won't be a waste of time to read through
		this. If so then it was not very much time.</p>

		<p>As this site will be changed soon, our Wiki now contains a <a
		href="http://openfacts.berlios.de/index-en.phtml?title=SimME_Development_Documentation">page
		dedicated to development documentation</a></p>

		<section><title>What do you need?</title>

			<p>Sure, there are a lot of different possibilities to develop for J2ME.
			This section shows the way we do it.</p>

			<table>
				<tr>
					<td valign="top">Wireless toolkit (WTK)</td>
					<td>
						This is the main development tool used. Compiling of sources,
						package deployment, emulation, etc. The newest version can be found
						at the <a
						href="http://java.sun.com/products/j2mewtoolkit/index.html">WTK
						site</a>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td valign="top">JUnit</td>
					<td>
						Needed to run the tests. <a
						href="http://www.junit.org/">www.junit.org</a>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td valign="top">IDE</td>
					<td>
						Any IDE is possible to edit your code. Some tools integrate more
						with the wireless tookit, while others do not. The choice depends on
						your taste. See a list of possible tools at <a
						href="http://wireless.java.sun.com/allsoftware/index.html#midpdev">http://wireless.java.sun.com/allsoftware/index.html#midpdev</a>
						(we use eclipse, which is not listed there)
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>

		</section>

		<section><title>How to use the Sources</title>

			<p>Create a directory in the <code>apps</code> directory of the WT. Put
			the sources <strong>without</strong> the testing package into the
			<code>src</code> directory within this newly created directory. Now you
			have two possibilities. Either you create a new project pointing to this
			direcotry, or you use our <code>.jad</code> file and put it into the
			<code>bin</code> directory.</p>

			<p>The testpackages may be put somewhere else (e.g.
			<code>testsrc</code>).</p>

		</section>

		<section><title>Helpful Documentation</title>

			<p>There are great books out there, but a lot of information is quite
			near:</p>

			<ul>
				<li>
					The program is intended for J2ME, so most information is directly at
					the source: <a
					href="http://java.sun.com/j2me/">java.sun.com/j2me</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					The <a href="http://wireless.java.com/">wireless java homepage</a> is
					a great place to find good information.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</section>

	</section>

</body>
</page>
