<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="website.xsl"?>
<page id="index">
	<meta>
		<title>SimME - Sim MicroEdition</title>
	</meta>

<body>

	<section>
		<title>
			SimME - <a href="http://developer.berlios.de/projects/simme/">@berlios</a>
		</title>

		<p>What does this stand for? <em><strong>Sim</strong>ulator
		<strong>M</strong>icro<strong>E</strong>dition</em>. In fact this project
		develops a two player game for Java 2 MicroEdition. The game is based on a
		strategy game which can be found at <a
		href="http://www.dbai.tuwien.ac.at/proj/ramsey/">www.dbai.tuwien.ac.at/proj/ramsey</a>
		(the simulator). The game will be played via mobile phone against any other
		person around the globe.</p>

		<p>A community page will be set up, providing rankings, stats and a
		possibility to match up. More on this soon.</p>

		<section><title>General Information</title>

			<p>This is the main web page with some current information on the project.
			The most current version is 0.0.5. You can download the release files from
			the <a
			href="https://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=730">files
			page</a>. Alternatively point your mobile phone to

			<blockquote>
				<p><a href="http://www.einspiel.at/">www.einspiel.at</a></p>
			</blockquote>

			in order to download the game directly to your phone.</p>

			<p class="notes">Note: the above URL is a WAP page and may be displayed
			incorrectly in some browsers.</p>

			<p>More information can be found at <a
			href="http://openfacts.berlios.de/index-en.phtml?title=SimME">our wiki
			page</a>.</p>

		</section>

		<section><title>Current Development</title>

			<p>We are currently working hard on our next release. For the curious:
			have a look at the project's <a
			href="http://cvs.berlios.de/cgi-bin/viewcvs.cgi/simme">CVS web
			interface</a>. Although some comments are in German, we tried to keep all
			javadoc in English.</p>

			<p>The project is split into two parts. One part builds the client side
			which uses the MIDP-1.0 and CLDC-1.0 specification. The other part
			develops the server side which uses JSPs/Servlets (where we don't have
			that much experience). The two parts communicate via XML over HTTP.</p>

			<p>Currently the development process is held very close but the project
			will soon be opened after we have created something someone else could
			use. There is a short introduction on the <a
			href="devel-environment.html">development environment</a>. Although it is
			not current, there are some links that can get you started.</p>

		</section>

		<section><title>Berlios</title>

			<p>A lot of thanks go to <a
			href="http://developer.berlios.de/">Berlios</a> who host the development
			pages of this project.</p>

			<p><A href="http://developer.berlios.de"><IMG
			src="http://developer.berlios.de/bslogo.php?group_id=730" width="124"
			height="32" border="0" alt="BerliOS Developer Logo"/></A></p>

		</section>

	</section>

</body>
</page>
